find your energy,
because it is time for us to get started.
The final session of the conference.
So this is it.
You look at the schedule in your time
zone.
All that is left
is our ELO award ceremony.
And the organization does this.
Every year is one of the ways
we celebrate all the amazing work
that happens throughout the community.
Please keep in mind that you are always
welcome to submit to the Yellow
Wash for the call around the same time
as next year's conference,
and we thank Jason for all of his work
putting this together
and that hand
it off to him to get started.
My kids, I'm Jason.
This year was an exciting year.
I'll just preface it by saying
the last couple years, Alinta and I.
So there are two organizers
of the awards myself
and my wife, partner
now mother of my child
and and a much better artist
and thinker and writer than myself.
Alinta Crawford
is in the other room currently.
But when we first agreed to do this.
Yes. The baby mama.
Absolutely.
When we first agreed to do this,
I don't think we anticipated
the challenges of
of giving birth to a child
and also then raising that child over
its first eight weeks of its life.
So we have not done a big fancy thing
like we have in the past.
We're just going to give out awards
because that's all that matters.
We're just going to give out awards.
So this year we have quite a few awards.
We have quite a few judges.
We will be releasing
all of the judges comments
and all the names of the judges
and all that over social media
and on the website.
But to keep things sort of moving,
because we don't have a lot of time
and we have a large number of awards
to give out, we're going to focus on
the winners and their voice tonight.
We had a lot of people submitting
this year, which is good for the field.
I think that is very, very exciting
and I can say
just off the top
judging, as always, was very hard.
I know it's a cliche to say that,
but it really was.
It really was this year.
And so if you submit it and you didn't
win, honestly, and you know,
the Earth
rotates 0.5 degrees differently
and you've won the award.
I mean, it was that close.
All right.
So this is an important asset.
That said before this is an important part
of what we do as an organization.
It's an important part,
I think, of a career
to be recognized by your peers.
And and it's no small task.
Everyone in the board is involved
in these kind of awards.
So why don't we begin?
So I'll share my screen.
We're going to begin with
my God.
Hold on just a second.
Okay, cool.
All right. I'll share my screen.
Hi, kids.
Okay, so here we are.
So we're going to begin
with the in Katherine Hale's award
for criticism of Electronic literature.
Now as a reminder, we have four
different awards that the low gives out.
We have one for scholarly
writing or criticism.
We have one for creative work.
We have one for achievement.
And we have the mysterious
and yet very coveted Maverick Award. So
the Hales winners, who
has won the Hales Award this year?
Let's find out now what we're going to do.
By the way, as I know,
winners are here. Maybe.
Maybe not.
We don't know when your name appears.
I want you to speak up,
and then I will attempt to spotlight you.
And you can say your piece.
So, honorable mention
this year of the Hales
Award is.
David Thomas.
Henry writes
digital literary created practice
six memos for writers
and the current millennium.
David, are you here?
Yeah. I'm here. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. Ello.
I gotta say, thank you very much to my
this nominated thesis project.
So thank you very much to my professor,
my supervisor, Professor Vijay
Mishra and Doctor Simone Lazar.
Thank you very much to Rutledge.
I also need to say thank you to the Jazz
Research Grant Foundation
in Japan
that supported this and Deni Gregoire.
Let me come and do some research
on this project at Vancouver.
So thank you very much to you.
Thank you to Jason and Joseph Tabby,
who both examined this PhD,
which ultimately came this project.
So thank you very much.
There's a lot of tentacles
stretching out within the yellow
that I'm really appreciative for.
Thank you very much.
Awesome.
David, that's super exciting.
And again, if you don't know,
David is a colleague of ours here
in the University of Bergen.
And honestly, I'm super excited, David,
that you have been given
an honorable mention.
I think it's very, very cool.
I have just accidentally spotlighted you.
All right. Moving on.
So after the honorable mention,
we now have runner
up, the runner up for the Hales Award is.
The Digital Future of English Literary
Media Studies by some.
Murray.
Are you here from?
I am here from Australia.
I'm. Yes, from a pre-dawn Melbourne.
I'm. Hello.
I'm really happy to to be here
and be joining you.
Here's here's the book as the cover.
You've already got it
there on the PowerPoint, I guess.
But I really wanted to say thank you
to the yellow for, for noticing this book,
because to be honest, I wasn't sure
if it was the kind of cup of tea
when I entered it, because it's not doing
textual analysis of a born digital work
in the way that we often do in the low.
It's really speaking from mainstream
literary studies and looking at how
digital technology changes
everything about the English discipline,
what it studies,
its methods, its theories,
its audiences that it speaks to,
and it's pedagogies as well.
So my thanks to the organization,
because it's fantastic to know
that a scholarly discipline is happy
to pop its head up and look over the fence
and sees what's happening, you know,
in the in the next door neighboring patch.
And not to be sort of ring
fencing disciplines in a in a narrow way.
That's really heartening to me.
So I appreciate it, and I hope
I will see you face to face in person
at the next terrestrial conference.
Awesome.
And again, super nice of you to show up.
Having lived in Australia
for a very long time,
I know how difficult it is
to get up in the morning this early.
So we really appreciate you being here.
All right, so the next award and
I realize I'm not actually pinning things
I think properly.
So I'll get to do that in a minute.
All right.
So the winner of this year's Hales Award.
Oh, God.
Hold on. Sorry.
Just show that again.
All right.
The winner of this year's Hales Award is.
The winner of the salesman is.
Why is it not doing it?
Oh, God. Oh. Thank kids.
Just a second.
I have missed something up badly.
Here we go. Okay.
The winner.
Can you all see my screen? No.
One more time.
Apologies.
I seem to be screwing this up.
All right.
The winner is
binding.
Media hybrid print, digital literature
from across the Americas.
Ortega, are you here?
I am here. Awesome.
Okay, well, hold on a second. Now,
I'm gonna see if I can figure this out.
So I'm going to stop sharing.
And I am currently pinned.
And does someone want to help me pin
our winner?
There we go.
Thank you.
Brilliant. Hi.
Hi. Congratulations.
Thank you. Jason.
Thank you everyone.
This is just such an incredible honor.
I'm kind of speechless.
My heart is racing right now.
This book took me
like ten years to write.
And I also visited Deanie.
I enjoyed her support.
I also enjoyed the support of miss
and of course, my colleague
Lori Emerson at University
Colorado Boulder.
Those labs, those resources
really made this, this book possible.
I love digital literature
and I also love madly print books.
So again, this is kind of like my love
letter to the field.
And and just, you know, thank you.
Thank you so much.
This is it is great to be to be awarded
this honor.
Also, Katherine, health
work has been just like the basis
of how I understand
these weird literary things that I like.
And I'm just happy to be able to do
what I hope
is a contribution to the field.
So thank you. Thank you so much.
Lovely.
Lovely again.
Congratulations.
That is very, very exciting.
All right.
So we will move on. Yeah, definitely.
Thank you to the judges.
I can say that the judges
really put in a massive effort again.
Their names will be published
on the website and social media,
but they did it last minute as well.
You know, we were under the gun in terms
of trying to finish everything
towards the last minute.
And they have really done an amazing job.
Indeed, we had people stepping in
at the last minute to help.
We really have a great community,
and you'll be very glad to know
that the name of the judges
for all the awards is AI.
So we used AI to judge everything
this year.
And so that's we've decided to do that.
So AI is decided to judge
judge everything.
Yeah, yeah.
We use the XS
AI whatever the hell is called.
Okay, so no, only humans stretch it.
You'll be glad to know.
All right, so let's move on.
We will now go to the Coover Award.
Now, if you don't know the Coover Award,
this is our award
that we give out for creative work.
The low, as I'm sure you know,
is one of those rare organizations
that supports equally creative work
and scholarly work.
And to show that support,
we have two different award,
two main awards
that we give out across those two areas.
So the Coover Award, this year's
Coover Award,
we have a lot of people to get through.
So you'll have to bear with me.
In fact,
I might just go ahead and read it off
and not use the PowerPoint
to make it a little bit easier.
All right.
So we're going to start with
the honorable mentions
of the Coover Award.
So this year, the first honorable mention
when I say your name,
you're going to have to get up there
and, you know, say something.
The very first one is
and this this is a person that I,
I'm worried about, I'm scared of,
honestly.
So the very first one is Vegard for
a small world.
Very first honorable mention. Vegard.
Hello.
Say something.
Could someone help me spot Vegard?
Can some of you might mean.
Can you hear me?
Yeah. We can. By the way, what is this?
Oh, this is my.
Done.
It's a love letter.
Okay, go.
Yeah.
Okay. Sorry.
Yeah. No.
Thank you so much. It is truly.
I'm truly honored to achieve this
honorable mention.
And I'd like to thank both
the crowd for her
amazing help in in creating it.
I'd also like to thank Jason Nelson
for for a lot of guidance
and being being a mentor and, and, and,
you know, not just the father
in real life, but a father to
me as well in many ways. And.
And my.
So okay. Sorry.
My partner I'd like to thank my partner.
I could just say this work has won.
A couple have been nominated
for a couple other words.
And so that is super exciting.
It's a really, really impressive
work from a person who I feel like is
is one of our fields up and comers.
So watch.
Watch this name, this name Vegard,
because it will appear many times.
What's the name of the work?
Vegard.
Oh, sorry.
The name of the work is one lonely world.
One lonely world.
I'll try to put up links.
We'll put up links and stuff
on social media when it comes out.
Yeah.
Awesome. Good.
Congratulations. Thank you.
We're going to move on.
All right,
so the next work that we want to next
honorable mention that we have here
is by Collier.
And the work is dioxin field.
You're here.
Hi. I'm here.
I can see myself.
Oh, there we go. Hi. Thank you.
This is really wonderful.
I mean, I think you guys all know
what it's like to make your own weird
little thing in your own space and hope
it has some meaning for somebody else.
So it's really exciting to know
that it's found some audience.
It's an immersive poem.
It's at the yellow exhibit.
You can look at it with some others
and company,
and it's written along a US military base
fence line in Okinawa where I grew up.
So I'm really interested in looking
at militarized spaces with a surveillance
I as an artist and citizen.
So that's kind of what
the whole project is.
I want to say thank you to Javy,
who I believe is in here somewhere,
who started me off thinking about
immersive and poetry together
like ten years ago
when we did a collaboration in Hong Kong
where I'm still based and where he was
based, and also thank utility,
who turned me on to ello in
the first place when she was in Hong Kong.
So I'm relatively new to yellow,
but I feel really at home here
because it's just like the best place
to feel comfortable.
And Dorking out about poetry,
digital, everything.
As you know it's great.
So thank you so much.
And one last thing.
I'm trying to bend this project
into something legible
as an academic monograph
for a ten year committee.
So if anybody has advice about that
I would be so grateful to hear it.
So thank you very much
for making a home for all this stuff.
I love the work, by the way.
Thank you.
That means a lot.
Really, really, really wonderful work.
All right.
So we have our third honorable mention.
Our third of all mentioned is now this
one is is really quite exciting to me.
The third one coming from
the south is a flight.
And I, I cannot pronounce that.
So I won't even try a flight over.
And I will let you pronounce
that over New Zealand.
You're here
also from the southern half of the world.
If someone can help me spotlight.
Yeah.
I'm here a flight over out New Zealand.
Oh thank you, thank you.
Oh, thank you so much.
Thank you Ellen members for this amazing,
very well organized conference.
Well, I'm a Brazilian
PhD candidate
at the University of Waikato,
and this research creation was
only possible thanks to the work of many
hands.
A huge thanks to my family
as of for the unconditional support.
And thank you to everyone
who collaboratively helped to co-create
a forward and Z is the acronym
and especially
the young authors
to collaborate with amazing letters.
I hope you enjoyed this
and visited the page A4, dot and Z.
Thank you so much.
Congratulations again!
I mean this was a really lovely work.
I especially loved the way that it
targeted, you know, kind of new audiences.
And yeah,
I found myself really, really enjoying it.
In fact, I'm looking forward to sharing it
with our our child
once can understand it, you know.
Yeah. Awesome. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
All right.
So moving on.
We now are going to go to the runner ups.
Now you know you leave you leave a link
to nine charge of the awards.
And we're going to break a few rules.
So we have actually have two runner ups.
Now I know that's unconventional.
I know that will make some of you
very angry and upset.
You'll just have to stomach it
I apologize.
All right.
So the two runners up are our first runner
up is a person
that some of you might know.
The work is called a million Random
Acts by Mark sample.
Mark, please say some words.
Yeah.
I'm here. Mark, y'all hear me? Okay,
we can hear you.
Just wait. Thanks.
I'll just say really quickly
I made a million random acts because I
wanted to make something that
if I run another state at another
university might get me fired.
And it gave me.
I haven't been, but.
But if I were somewhere else, I might be.
I just want to thank a few people.
So Stephanie Strickland and Nick
Montfort's scenes far between from,
you know what, 2013
or so that kind of opened my eyes to grid
based, you know, procedural literature
and a million random acts.
Is is obviously inspired by that.
Lily and Yvonne Bertram's edited
edition of Michigan Literary Quarterly
Review, that Michigan Quarterly Review
that a million random acts was was in.
So thank you
for letting me to bond for that.
I want to thank Daniel Howell
for his fantastic Rita JavaScript library.
That's kind of
the textual engine of the piece.
And then Lauren McCarthy for her P5, js,
which is the visual engine of the piece.
And, you know,
I couldn't have done any of this without
the work of everybody that came before.
And I could just say that, Mark,
you submit
two works this year
and the judges like both of them,
but the judges
were particularly impressed, I think, by
how this million random acts kind of met
the current moment in the world.
And we definitely recognized
and I love this.
I love when works borrow
from different sort of styles
or approaches
from previous works in the field.
That really shows how much art field
has matured and changed over time.
So yeah, just a brilliant work.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you so much. Awesome.
All right.
So moving on.
Our second runner up
this year is now we've done something
a little bit of unusual this year.
We're not giving it out to a human.
The second one we're giving to a robot.
Not kidding.
We're not giving it to robots.
So the second one that we have
this year is Powell Rodriguez
and also I power IAO.
I'm not sure
if I'm saying your artist name right.
But this is UVB 76.
A poetic artifact is the second runner up.
And you're here today, right?
Maybe not.
Hello?
Oh. You're here. Here we go.
Yeah, yeah.
There you are. Hey.
Well, thank you very much
for selecting my poem as a runner up.
My work is about the end of the world.
It is also about the end of the world.
The words of a language.
My language that is dying.
So thank you for helping to leave a record
that Catalan once existed.
And now allow me to end with a few records
on my own language.
Language? Sorry.
El premi.
Kim. Gracias.
Thank you.
Brilliant work.
Seriously. Thank you.
Thank you so much again.
The judges were impressed
by this really complex and work.
Mysterious, actually.
And I'm a big fan.
A big fan of mysterious works.
So yeah, it's really, really cool.
All right, so moving on.
We're going to go to the winner of
this year's Coover Award.
So the winner.
Now, this is exciting.
Very exciting. The winner.
The winner is.
Flesh and Blood by Chris Joseph.
That is this year's winner.
Chris.
Yes, we can hear you.
Chris I I'm a fan.
I just have to say, I am a fan
and I've been a fan for a long time.
And go ahead and talk.
Thank you.
Jason.
And congratulations to you
and the lens as well.
I'm a major still up at this time.
So thank you.
Thank you so much.
To win an award with Robert Kluver
name on it from the organization
he helped found is about as meaningful
as it can be in our field.
So I'm hugely, hugely honored
and grateful to you.
For those who don't know anything
about this piece, Flesh and Blood
as a digital fiction, it's about memory,
the body, identity and loss.
The reader kind of awakens
in a surreal, slightly
nightmarish environment, and to progress,
they have to work through various scenes,
gentle puzzles to find out the reality
of their situation in the world.
It uses sound, video,
images and games,
and something I really wanted
to try and do in this piece
was two slightly different text groups,
one shorter visually LED route and one
which is longer text centric.
I mean, there's a lot I can say about it,
but really, I want to talk
more about the ELO and white matter
so much to me.
Getting funding for
this work is always a challenge,
and getting recognition is amazing.
So although the funders might not always
understand
what you're trying to do, the yellow does.
And that's amazing.
It doesn't just recognize makers,
it promotes the work,
it distributes it
and crucially, archives it.
So that work which might be sitting
right, breaking somewhere
or disappearing, is kept
and seen and studied.
And that's amazing.
And that work is under amorous.
But it's essential.
And I thank you very much for it.
So in receiving this award,
I just wanted to say huge thank you
back to the community
and for keeping a chair
free for this kind of work, which often
has nowhere else to sit comfortably.
Thank you.
And seriously, thank you, thank you.
I mean, I think everyone was impressed
by this sort of combination
of poetic and story and visuals
and sound that you put into this work.
And also, I mean, I will say
I was a big fan of the other work
that you submitted as well,
where you sort of rethought.
The game.
And yeah,
I thought that was super fun actually.
But again,
I'm a big fan and congratulations,
I've loved your work for a very long time.
And I don't mean to keep gushing, but,
you know, it's just it's it's
well well deserved. Well deserved.
Awesome.
Thank you so much. Great.
All right. So moving on.
We have two more awards
that we're going to give out this year.
We have the Maverick Award
and then we have the Marjorie Lens
Brick Career Achievement Award
which is super exciting.
Now the maverick word has been around
for a couple of years,
and we've had quite an eclectic mix
of of winners.
We had as we've had across all of this
missions.
This year.
We had quite a few people
submit a list of list of names and works
and scholarly outcomes and creative works
that I think we're really broad.
You know,
I think in the past
people have said that the ELO is a bit
of an insular organization.
But I think that the submissions
this year really shows
that this is a field, this is an area
that has broadened out considerably.
All right.
So moving on.
So the maverick word this year
was a tough tough call.
We had quite a few interesting names
submitted.
But this is a person
who has been involved
in the field of digital poetry,
involved in the field of,
of sort of generative digital art
and evolved in the field of creative
coding, involved in helping
both connected directly to the yellow,
but also directly connected
to a range of other communities.
It's a it's a person
who a lot of people sight
as being an inspiration
over a very, very long time.
And and I will just say briefly,
a brief story
is that I had known to this person's work
for a very long time.
They had published my work, and a bunch
of other people's work had been somewhat
promoted, really experimental work,
for a very, very long time.
And I remember meeting this person
for the first time in Canada,
and I don't think we knew
what to make of each other.
But I just, you know,
I'm really happy to say
that this year's
maverick word is given out to
Jim Andrews.
Jim, thanks so much, Jason,
and thanks so much to the yellow
and a bunch of people I'd like to thank.
Like to thank my parents
because I wouldn't
although I've been involved in this,
you know, for a long time
since I've been doing my site since 1996,
I couldn't have done it
without without them
leaving me enough money
so that I could, you know, I'm not rich.
They weren't rich, but they left me
enough money that I could do this
pretty much full time
since, you know, since like 1995.
And so
thanks also to my wife, Natalie.
It'll be 13 years for us this year.
So thank you, my dear.
Thanks also to Adina
Carrasco and Cédric James.
These are dear friends of mine
and we've been a lot of collaboration.
Thanks also to Lionel Kern.
He's he's a poet who is from Vancouver
and he, he, he,
he was writing about digital poetry,
digital art back in 1964 and
wrote a whole
book on really interesting
experimental media and computer stuff,
digital art, back in 1964,
and we've done a lot of collaboration.
We're still collaborating.
And to Joe Keppler in Seattle.
He he sort of
he was my my mentor.
He, he introduced me to.
Poly poetry, to poly art.
And to Chris Joseph.
I mean, Chris is well,
I've known Chris since,
I guess probably about 19,
1997, something like that.
We met in Ottawa
and he he's he's one of the few people
who produced an amazing work
amount of work,
wonderful work in flash
and now has retooled
to to JavaScript, CSS
and is also, as you can see,
if you've seen his amazing work
that just won the Coover
Prize, he's taking it to another level
with these AI tools that,
you know, promise to
give us a different sort of level of work
and maybe type of work in the future.
And and also my old friend Ted Warnow
and Leo Flores and Dean
Gregoire
and the late Randy Adams and Peter,
an interesting computer
artist here in Vancouver, who's also Stan
Douglas is main programmer,
and Gregory Whitehead,
whom I've been following since 1983 or 84,
got to be the most amazing audio artist
in the world.
Audio writer.
And and also to not last
but not least to Alan Sondheim,
who has been kind of an inspiration
for very long time,
going back to like 97, 98.
And we fought like cats and dogs,
but, but,
but finally we came to be friends,
and I admire him so much.
So, you know,
even though we're in this time
of, of, of climate
change and fascism, I think it's,
I think it's an intense time
for digital writing,
not least of which because of these
AI tools that that are very much oriented
towards
writers, it's text to whatever.
So I think writers are in
a really interesting position
amongst all the arts
to take these tools
and do really interesting things
with them.
I'm currently working on a piece called
arteries 2026,
which is a kind of a redoing
of a piece that I did in 2001,
and it's the battle
of poetry against itself
and the forces of darkness,
and it's a shoot em up poetry game,
but this version is less guni more text,
a text, it shoots
texts, people are shooting texts,
and there's there's boss monster poets.
There's,
you know, like about 16 boss monster poets
who are very tough characters and,
and they're shooting
text and ideas and,
and there's all sorts of new features.
So this isn't just a, you know, a
redoing of a work from 2000
that I did in director,
but instead with these tools, I'm able to
to take it to a different level
and all sorts of interesting new features.
And so I think what we're going to see is,
is, you know, a situation
where we've got something
like what happened with Flash
and Shockwave, if you remember,
if you're if you're old enough
to remember those things
Flash and Shockwave produced,
there was a lot of really wonderful work
produced in
with those tools
and then they disappeared.
But now we have these AI tools.
And so I think we're going to see people
who who can't code
producing some amazing works,
and then also those who can code
are going to be able to take it
to a totally different level.
And then also I want to mention
that there's going to be a pool,
a version of of of Art 2026,
which is a, you know, progressive web app.
So you can app a website
and you can turn it into an app
that can go into the,
the stores, the app stores.
And also I'm hoping
to sell it from my own site.
So this has been a problem
for a long time.
Being able not being able
to sell your work, basically like a book,
you know, you produce a website of stuff
and it's been very difficult to sell it.
But these PWAs really offer
an interesting way to produce an app
that people can buy
and install on their computer,
like a regular app.
And so if anybody's interested
in working on creating a store
of this sort of work,
please let me know, because I think
a publisher of that nature,
you know, some a publisher that could
that could sell really interesting
digital art apps would be pretty exciting.
And so thanks again, Jason,
thanks so much and
wonderful to meet you for the second time.
And I've admired your work
for a very long time.
So thanks to everybody.
And seriously,
Jim, I can reveal, by the way,
that the person nominated you was Chris
Joseph.
Well, I shouldn't say that, by the way.
We don't normally
we don't normally reveal that.
But, you know, I just did.
But I mean, yeah,
I mean, Jim, seriously, as you can,
if you read through the comments here,
which you should,
you will see that
that people in this community
think you're an amazing choice
for the Maverick Award.
And honestly, I mean, you know,
Jesus, your your work has always been
very influential to me personally.
And being one of the judges
for the Maverick board this year, having
won it last year,
I can say that I'm just super chuffed
that you were nominated
and that that that we're able to sort of
honor you in this way and,
and your work continues.
I mean, God, you just good at it,
you know?
So it's always, always very impressive.
Thank you all.
I feel like I have a new lease
on life with these these new AI tools.
You know, I feel like I'm producing
my best work now.
So brilliant.
Again,
thank you so much.
All right. Thank you.
So we have one more award to give out.
Sorry.
Hold on.
You know, it's funny, actually.
You learn to identify the kind of cries
like, I'm learning to read baby cry.
I'm learning to speak baby cry.
And so I'm hearing a baby cry.
And it sounds like just an annoyed cry.
Not a not a cry of alarm.
Okay,
so we have one more award to give out.
This is the Marjorie Lunsford.
There was a
brief spoken thing there.
Okay. We have one more word to give out.
So this year
our final ward goes to and and
and this is a person who,
I mean, you know, depending
on your understanding of this word,
I think we could
all agree is a God in the field.
G.H. de so this year this award goes to.
Joe Tabby.
Brilliant.
Joe I'm just going to say
that as I've been
speaking before,
everyone else is, you know,
for all the awards,
we had a large number of submissions
and we had a lot of of people
who really had contributed a great deal
to this field.
But you were nominated for this award,
and I'm not kidding
when I say this 14 times this year alone.
14 times.
I mean, I'm looking at this list,
this Excel sheet, right?
And it's like Joe, tabby,
Joseph, tabby, Joe,
Joey, tabby, Joseph
and what I know, I know.
So just brilliant.
Yeah.
The thing about that,
if every one of them read an article
sends it to me,
it'll go get published in ever.
And so,
you know, being in the Maverick seat
gives you that flexibility
to get the list of rank seat, the lucid
dream, the fancy career achievement award.
Yeah, yeah. Who?
You know, with Lucid
and Strickland got me started in
this field.
Okay.
You know, I had the literature
and, you know, was doing doing fine there.
And then I brought that into the digital
framework.
And I mean,
and Joe, you know,
I can say that in terms of you're
reading through all these comments
that that people have made
about your career and it's amazing.
I mean, you know, there's one thing
to talk about the scholarship
someone has produced.
There's one thing to talk about,
you know, the artwork
let's say someone's produced.
But there's another thing to talk about
how how someone has has literally created
whole new tendrils in a field
and has inspired people and helped people.
I mean, your
your work has reached out to thousands,
and what you've done has helped thousands.
Look at Rob
comments and
and Dina and Leo and Caitlin,
everyone is singing praise.
He's he's he's reading it.
Jason should I
can I read the the the the judges.
Yeah.
It's just it's just really and you know,
and it's interesting that something like
Eber, for example, which is continuing
and thriving under under
new leadership,
under your advice, under your,
you know, what you've built
has, has
I don't know, it's just all inspiring.
And I just tell you a brief story, Joe.
I remember I went to a conference and I
first sort of conference I've been to.
I didn't know anything.
I was kind of a weirdo.
And I remember you stood up and you made
a comment about something I had said,
and your comment was positive and,
oh my God, I wrote that positive comment.
I think for, for like three years,
you know, it was like, wow,
that's super nice and that kind of thing
that you've done for so many people in
this field has just been incredible.
I would
love to give the official judges
statement
on behalf of the committee,
and I also want to thank the judges.
I think at least one of them is here.
I saw them, but Joe,
you should be showered with praise.
So I wanted to make that official and I'm
outing myself as a committee member.
And also that's
why I'm here. I don't live in Rochester.
I drove here to because I'm
going to get him drunk after this. So.
All right,
the description of the Marjorie Psilocybin
Career Achievement Award states
that it seeks to honor a visionary artist
and or scholar who has brought excellence
to the field of electronic literature
and has inspired others to help create
and build the field.
For this, and for so many other reasons,
we've chosen as this year's
recipient, Professor Joseph Paul.
Tabby Joe has spent more than three
decades building the intellectual
and infrastructural foundations
upon which the field
of electronic literature
now stands as the founding editor,
as one of the founding editor in Chief,
editors in chief of Electronic Book
Review, one of the oldest online
academic journals.
Launched in 1995
and sustained in continuous publication
for 30 years, Joe
was integral in creating what colleagues
described as an essential hub
for cutting edge, critical, resource
critical discourse, one that emerged
well before terms like open access or
digital humanities had entered common use.
As one nominator put it, quote,
Joe did not follow the field
he built, the terrain
on which it could emerge, unquote.
That's said that I'll tell you later,
I actually don't know.
It's anonymous. That same spirit.
You should let me know if you said that
that same spirit
of foundational leadership
carried through his service as president
of the Electronic Literature Organization
from 2007 to 2010,
his long tenure on its board of directors,
his revitalization
of the Electronic Literature Directory,
and his founding role in the Consortium
on Electronic Literature sell.
Oh, I've got more.
Beyond infrastructure,
Joe's scholarship has shaped
how the field understand itself.
His editorial vision produced The Blues
Very Handbook of Electronic Literature,
winner of the Ellos
and Catherine Hills Award for Criticism
of Electronic Literature,
and its companion
volume, Post Digital Dialogs and Debates
from Electronic Book Review, together
forming what one nominator, one nominator
called, quote, the most authoritative
scholarly infrastructure
the field of electronic literature
possesses, unquote.
His authored works,
including Postmodern Sublime, Cognitive
Fictions and most recently, The Cambridge
Introduction to Literary Posthuman ism,
further demonstrates
a career devoted equally to critical rigor
and and to the communities
that sustain it.
As another colleague of 30 years
reflected, quote,
no single individual has done
more to build the intellectual
and infrastructural foundations
of electronic literature as a field.
And above
all, Joe is well known for his generosity
as a mentor and community builder,
supporting early career
scholars, including myself,
through the ELO fellows program,
connecting artists and academics across
national and institutional lines
and inspiring the careers
of countless practitioners
who now carry
the feel for the field forward.
And I will just leave it with by saying
that another nominator wrote that quote
without his talent, attention
and care for both academic excellence
and community building,
neither ELO nor electronic literature
would have been there
would have been where they are today.
And for these reasons,
Joseph Tabby is an exemplary recipient
of this year's
Marjorie Career Achievement Award.
And can I ask everyone, turn on your audio
and let's let let's give
let's give Joe some cheers and applause.
So go ahead.
Congratulations.
Thank you, thank you.
Well it's it's well earned, Joe.
And thanks for all of your contributions
throughout the years.
Really. We wouldn't we wouldn't.
The yellow would not be what it is
without you.
And the the field wouldn't be what it is
So, so grateful. Joe.
Yeah.
You're welcome.
That's. That's.
Cheers. Cheers. Cheers.
Cheers.
Cheers to Joe.
I don't I don't know what's in there, but.
Brilliant.
Yeah, absolutely.
All right. So thank you lychee.
Thank you Joe.
Thank you to all the winners.
Thank you to the judges.
As I said, we will be posting all
about to send these to Mark marksman,
you know, bugging me about it.
Send all the judges comments
and we'll have links and arrange
the things to all the winners on
our social media as well as the website.
But that concludes the awards
for this year.
And little Sebastian,
little Sebastian Silo,
who's in the other room,
wanted to come out and say hello.
But frankly, nap time is too important.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Too important. All right.
We love you all.
You all love each other.
And this has been an amazing conference.
And I think we all agree that Anastasia
and her team
deserves the giant test of applause.
This has been an amazing,
amazing conference.
And and,
you know, really impressed by everything.
So thank you to everybody.
All right, Anastasia,
you want to say anything more?
This this is it, folks.
We are wrapping.
Thank you all for entrusting of us
with your work, for
joining us in our effort to build
all of these open access resources
that will outlive
even our time in person at the conference.
For joining us with my check out.
Nick Montfort has adorable baby
and adorable cats and dogs
and other Lyle has has one right now.
All of our kind of home
companions have been a part of
and been disrupted by our weeks of work,
and we really appreciate you
taking the time
to join us for all of this.
Enjoy the rest of your weekend and.
Please,
when you are arrested,
come back, explore the archive and catch
all of the things
that you weren't able to catch live.
Says thank you.
Hi everybody.
But she's also had it with being on a desk
and is very happy
to finally go take a walk.
So I hope all of you
come showing us in 2027.
You're all very excited to be headed south
and to gather in person again.
We'll see you then.
Yes. You all by.
Scott, can you send a zoom link, please?